‪When I saw she was playing dumb,
‪I knew that was my chance.
‪Amamiya probably likes her.
‪And the feeling's probably mutual.
‪But…
‪she'll never make the first move.
‪She'll just pile on the excuses
‪and keep pretending not to notice.
‪She's a coward whose sole interest
‪is making sure she doesn't get hurt.
‪She won't do things for herself.
‪She needs other people to make her happy.
‪She's a passive waiter.
‪I hate that.
‪EPISODE 15
‪CLOUDS AND RAIN
‪The Meiten band is having a concert soon.
‪Has Akahoshi or anyone else mentioned it?
‪Now that you mention it,
‪I think I might have heard.
‪Would you like to go with me?
‪My friend is going to be there,
‪so I'd like to go and see it.
‪But I'm too scared to go alone.
‪Sure. Let's go.
‪Let's invite some others
‪who might be interested too.
‪The more the merrier, right?
‪That's true.
‪Oh, sorry.
‪That's all I had to say.
‪I just thought it'd be faster
‪to call you rather than to type it out.
‪Faster, huh?
‪Well, I'll be in touch
‪closer to the date, okay?
‪Sure. Thanks.
‪LIFT
‪SIDE PLANK
‪It won't stop raining.
‪MEITEN HIGH SCHOOL
‪I like you.
‪How should I act around Yota
‪when I see him in class today?
‪Would it be callous of me
‪to just talk like normal?
‪But it'd hurt more
‪to just avoid him, right?
‪Wait, I can't even
‪reciprocate his feelings.
‪Aren't I being lordly
‪by thinking of these things?
‪What do I do?
‪Miki.
‪Good morning.
‪Did you study for today's language quiz?
‪WHAT!!!
‪That was today? Oh, crap!
‪There's still time. You'll be fine.
‪Just memorize the handout.
‪There you go again.
‪"Just memorize," he says.
‪You say it like it's that easy!
‪Geez!
‪Good luck. You've got this.
‪Yota. We're going now.
‪Oh, wait.
‪All right. I'll see you later.
‪He's too kind…
‪BANANA JUICE
‪All right, Miki.
‪Something happened, didn't it?
‪Nothing happened.
‪Here. Drink this.
‪AGGRESSIVE SIP
‪Hey, Minato…
‪You readily go out with people
‪even when you don't like them, don't you?
‪Huh? Wait, was that a diss?
‪Have you ever turned someone down
‪after they tell you how they feel?
‪I guess not.
‪Why not?
‪There may be no reason to date them,
‪but there's also
‪no reason to not date them.
‪I never hated any of them.
‪What about after?
‪Do you ever wish
‪you hadn't gone out with them?
‪I think…
‪they're the ones
‪who regret going out with me.
‪I'm the one who always gets dumped.
‪I figured if they don't need me anymore,
‪there's not much I can do about that.
‪I wonder if it hurt for those girls
‪that you didn't feel
‪the same way toward them.
‪UM, AM I BEING ATTACKED?
‪FEELING GUILTY
‪I hope one day,
‪you fall in love with someone
‪who doesn't care about you at all.
‪I hope she tramples all over your heart.
‪SMILE
‪Yeah. Probably.
‪Unrequited love hurts.
‪I know that now.
‪You're right, Miki.
‪I probably did do something bad
‪to the girls I've dated so far.
‪So it does end up that way, huh?
‪It doesn't work out.
‪Hey, wait.
‪Did somebody try and ask you out
‪and you're wondering
‪whether to turn them down?
‪Crap.
‪Now I've really put my foot in it.
‪No.
‪I already turned them down.
‪What?
‪So it's all over now.
‪I mean, I already knew
‪nothing would ever come of it.
‪But I do feel better
‪after getting it off my chest.
‪Yeah? Really?
‪Yeah.
‪But at the same time,
‪I'm like, "Wow, it's really over."
‪It's been this huge thing
‪inside of me all this time,
‪and now there's just
‪this big, gaping hole left.
‪I kinda…
‪want to hurry up and fill it.
‪Yota.
‪It's okay to--
‪Oh, he's not crying.
‪Sorry, I thought you might
‪want a handkerchief.
‪Thanks. I'm fine.
‪Do people normally cry
‪at times like these?
‪I sort of can't cry, you see?
‪I did feel sad at graduation,
‪and when we lost the final game,
‪but maybe I've just given up on all that,
‪because that's just how it goes.
‪My feelings always escape through tears,
‪but Yota bottles his up.
‪I like this person,
‪but only as a friend.
‪You don't see them as a romantic partner?
‪I did date a few people
‪back in middle school.
‪They'd give me their details,
‪and the vibes were totally there.
‪HUH? ME?
‪WHO?
‪It was like, I could definitely
‪see us as romantic partners.
‪HE SEEMS LIKE A NICE GUY
‪I'd go out with them,
‪thinking I might like them back, but…
‪DUMPED AGAIN!!!
‪But it never worked out.
‪Each and every single time,
‪I felt like I was being rejected.
‪But then again, it's not like I was ever
‪serious about them either, so…
‪HMPH, FINE
‪FORGET YOU
‪So I've never
‪actually been in love before.
‪I was always just happy
‪to have somebody who likes me.
‪So to go out with someone
‪while I'm not feeling it yet, I…
‪I'd basically just be
‪stringing him along, right?
‪I… I'd hate myself for that.
‪So…
‪I think this is… the right decision.
‪And yet…
‪it hurts so much.
‪Do you wish Yota had always
‪only ever treated you as a friend?
‪Wait!
‪-How'd you know?
‪-It's clearly Yota, right?
‪It's obvious.
‪So I…
‪So I'm the only one who never knew.
‪When I said "I love you"
‪and "I'm so glad we're friends," I…
‪I'm so stupid… So heartless…
‪I hate that about myself.
‪What do I do?
‪This hurts so much.
‪You haven't done anything wrong, Miki.
‪It's not Yota's or anyone's fault.
‪Imagine finding out someone
‪who you thought was a friend
‪actually liked you as something more?
‪To think they see you differently…
‪I'd feel a bit disgusted.
‪Wouldn't you agree?
‪CRACK
‪When you fall in love with someone,
‪it just happens,
‪whether you realize it or not.
‪Even if the other person
‪doesn't reciprocate.
‪But what's more…
‪Koyun did say she'd never see her friends
‪as potential love interests.
‪You know you're faced
‪with potentially getting hurt.
‪Who am I trying to convince here?
‪I…
‪These feelings of mine…
‪Man, I'm starved.
‪There you are!
‪Hello there.
‪PEOPLE WHO FORMED GROUPS
‪DURING THE CHEER SQUAD
‪Oh, Kuriki.
‪I'm going to the upcoming concert.
‪I'm really excited for it.
‪Oh, you are?
‪Yep! With Amamiya.
‪WELL, WELL…
‪Are you two… a thing?
‪It's not that.
‪We were thinking of inviting
‪other people as well.
‪Although I'll bet he's just dodging
‪because I'm coming on so strong.
‪TEEHEE!
‪DODGING?
‪See you!
‪Amamiya dodging?
‪Think it's in her head?
‪Must be.
‪Either way,
‪I fear she's gonna end up in tears.
‪GRADE 2 CLASS 2
‪Miki.
‪Are you working today?
‪Hmm? No.
‪Can we… talk somewhere after?
‪Sure.
‪Don't often get invited by Koyun.
‪There's all sorts I want to ask her.
‪YOU OKAY?
‪ANYTHING YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT?
‪But I also haven't told her a lot.
‪ABOUT YOTA
‪ABOUT AMAMIYA
‪And about Amamiya…
‪IT'S EMBARRASSING
‪But it's embarrassing
‪to bring it up after all this time.
‪I WANT TO GET IT OFF MY CHEST
‪I've never even acknowledged it myself.
‪WHAT IF I MAKE HER FEEL AWKWARD?
‪All these thoughts
‪swirling around inside my head.
‪I'm scared of how it will all come out.
‪Is this a serious talk?
‪Does she need advice? What do I do?
‪Actually, about Yota, I…
‪What do I do, and how much
‪do I say if that's what this is about?
‪Yota?
‪Wanna grab food on the way home?
‪Sure. You can lay it all on me.
‪I didn't mean it like that.
‪SOGGY
‪Hey, these are the best ones.
‪Miki.
‪Listen, there's something
‪I need to tell you.
‪I…
‪-Amamiya--
‪-It's been forever, huh?
‪Feels like you always
‪turn me down for these things, Yota.
‪That's not true.
‪What? Is that you-know-who next to us?
‪No, there's no question about it.
‪You sure about that? Well, okay.
‪-Yota!
‪-Amamiya!
‪So, Minato.
‪Yeah?
‪Are you going out with Kurita?
‪So, Minato.
‪Kurita?
‪-Who's that?
‪You mean Kuriki?
‪Yeah, the girl in first year.
‪Why are you asking about her?
‪Because you two are going
‪to a concert together.
‪It's only a concert.
‪I was going to invite
‪some others along as well.
‪Wanna come?
‪Listen.
‪Ever since middle school,
‪you've always been
‪too "friendly" with the girls.
‪You know it gets their hopes up.
‪Should we be listening in on this?
‪But we can't exactly pull out now.
‪How many times have you dated
‪and broken up because of it now?
‪I thought Yota had come to me
‪for once to get something off his chest.
‪But now he's attacking me.
‪Just like Miki did…
‪Are you telling me I should outright
‪reject anyone I'm not interested in?
‪Is it really better to reject outright
‪even when there's no hate involved?
‪I'm not saying to reject outright, but…
‪But you shouldn't lead people on.
‪Do you say that because you
‪didn't like it when somebody led you on?
‪This has nothing to do with Miki!
‪I'm sorry.
‪I'm sorry too.
‪I hit him where it hurts…
‪WELLING UP
‪Yota…
‪Crap… I still haven't
‪told Koyun about this…
‪How much do you know?
‪I'm sorry. I know everything.
‪Sorry for putting you in a tough spot.
‪No, it's fine.
‪Minato.
‪Have you ever been in love?
‪Love?
‪Yeah. As in, no one can replace them,
‪or you feel they're the only one for you.
‪I…
‪I feel that way about everyone.
‪I feel that way about you,
‪and I feel that way about Miki.
‪You're both irreplaceable friends to me.
‪What about Koyun?
‪Koyun's great, isn't she?
‪BA-BUMP BA-BUMP
‪We all hang out together.
‪And you get along with her, right?
‪Do you have any special feelings for her?
‪Koyun…
‪I like her.
‪She's my friend.
‪So I love her.
‪I see.
‪Well, I'd love to see you in love someday.
‪Well, who knows?
‪How am I ever gonna show it to you?
‪I hate the rainy season.
‪It's so humid.
‪Koyun.
‪I'm sorry, Miki. I…
‪I've fallen for him.
‪Yota--
‪I like Amamiya.
‪Wait, what? Hold up. Hold it right there.
‪I'm sorry I couldn't say anything.
‪I wasn't even sure about how I felt.
‪I hadn't even thought about
‪how I wanted things to turn out,
‪so I couldn't tell you.
‪WAIT
‪I CAN'T
‪Wait… I can't do this…
‪So all this time, I…
‪Do not try to wile your way in
‪with Koyun like that.
‪I'd totally ship them.
‪LOSING HER VOCABULARY
‪Crap… I can't…
‪Crap, this sucks, this is all so crappy!
‪I think I'm gonna hurl.
‪Miki…
‪I honestly haven't even thought
‪about how I wanted it to turn out.
‪And he did just say
‪we're "just friends," so…
‪No! By hurl, I meant
‪how I feel toward myself.
‪I always thought
‪it was more like this!
‪But I…
‪But I… Back then, you…
‪ALL MISUNDERSTANDINGS HAVE BEEN CLEARED
‪Does this mean I've been blocking
‪Yota's love life all this time?
‪Definitely not!
‪Either way, I've only ever seen
‪Yota as just a friend.
‪Miki.
‪Remember how you mentioned
‪love being the "cherry on top"?
‪You wouldn't want that to be Yota?
‪Hypothetically,
‪let's say I come out to you and say
‪I've had feelings for you all this time.
‪Could you then turn around and say,
‪"Okay, I now feel the same way about you"?
‪I…
‪I don't think I can do it that easily.
‪I'm more miserable than happy
‪at being asked out.
‪But then I have another side
‪that thinks it'd be easier
‪if I could just fall for the person
‪who's fallen in love with me.
‪I thought I'd only end up hurting him if I
‪said yes while feeling so half-hearted,
‪so I said no.
‪But it still hurts.
‪So what should I have done?
‪Miki. Listen.
‪Yota's feelings for you…
‪are not of a sexual nature.
‪SEXUAL NATURE
‪He doesn't want to be with you
‪for your body or to have sex with you.
‪Koyun!
‪Yota likes you as a friend too.
‪He genuinely sees you for who you are.
‪He's only ever thinking of ways
‪that he can make you happy.
‪He's not out for you to make him happy.
‪That's the kind of person he is.
‪So,
‪don't be hard on yourself
‪for whatever happens with him.
‪To me… You're just Miki.
‪Today, I…
‪Yota came over to my seat today,
‪and I couldn't look at him.
‪I'll try to be more normal tomorrow…
‪Okay.
‪CLICKETY-CLACK
‪PUFFY EYES
‪So, what are you gonna do?
‪Huh? What do you mean?
‪Are you going to tell Minato
‪how you feel about him?
‪No. No, I won't.
‪From my perspective, this is the first
‪you've brought this up with me,
‪so I'd like to support you on this.
‪Thanks.
‪But now I know
‪he only sees me as a friend.
‪I'd like to revert my feelings
‪now while I can.
‪And doesn't Amamiya as a friend
‪sound much more fun anyway?
‪It'd probably be too hard for me to win
‪him over with so little dating experience.
‪CAN'T DENY THAT
‪Let's all hang out as friends again.
‪Yeah.
‪Is it really better to reject outright
‪even when there's no hate involved?
‪Amamiya is kind
‪and affectionate toward everyone
‪just as a matter of course.
‪I thought it was meant just for me,
‪and my feelings ran with it.
‪I…
‪I've been so stupid.
‪It's okay.
‪This is still fine.
‪I can forget.
‪It's not like I entered this
‪wanting to be his girlfriend.
‪I even treated him the way I did back when
‪we were first getting to know each other.
‪She's my friend.
‪So I love her.
‪Just hearing him say that
‪is enough for me.
‪In fact, maybe I should even
‪be questioning my feelings for him.
‪I'm the one who usually rejects people.
‪So I…
‪I must have just been feeling lonely.
‪And if that's the case, I'm okay now.
‪If I can be satisfied with things
‪as they are now, I won't feel lonely.
‪These feelings I have,
‪I can force them back to square one.
‪Good morning.
‪GRADE 2 CLASS 2
‪What's this? You're in early today, Miki.
‪Minato! Good morning!
‪Good morning, Koyun!
‪Good morning.
‪Good morning, Yota!
‪I love that energy. Good morning.
‪At this rate,
‪these feelings of mine
‪come across as nothing more
‪than a cruel joke.
‪How can she ever fall for me
‪if I keep treating her this way?
‪Subtitle translation by: Rychelle Brittain